Guide to the Charles A. Gulliver Photographs of Yale and New Haven
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Charles A. Gulliver photographs of Yale and New Haven
1870-1890
RU 642
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
The materials consist of photographs of Yale and New Haven, Connecticut in the late nineteenth-century. Included are views of various student rooms, academic buildings, and well-known university and New Haven scenes. Some photographs are of other institutions, including Princeton, Dartmouth, Harvard, and Vassar. Also inclued is a photograph of Charles A. Gulliver's college book store on Chapel Street.
Gulliver, Charles A.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-A (YRG 46-A), Records and materials broadly documenting Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased by Mr. Farr from the Gulliver family of West Haven, 1950.
Arrangement
Arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs of Yale and New Haven, Connecticut in the late nineteenth-century. Included are views of various student rooms, academic buildings, and well-known university and New Haven scenes. Some photographs are of other institutions, including Princeton, Dartmouth, Harvard, and Vassar. Also inclued is a photograph of Charles A. Gulliver's college book store on Chapel Street.
College buildings; New Haven (Conn.) -- Pictorial works; Photographs; Gulliver, Charles A.; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Students
- Photographs, Series I
  - original List by Hollon A. Farr (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #1 Chapel Street east from High Street (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #2 S.S.S. Mechanical Engineering Group (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #3 Chapel Street west from College Street (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #4 S.S.S. Chemical Engineering Group (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #5 Hamilton Park entrance, Whalley Avenue, Yale's Field (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #6 Savin Rock, Sea View House (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #7 Temple Street south to north (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #8 East Rock toward the harbor (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #9 1876 trophies (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #10 toward cornerof Chapel and College Street (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #11 Elm Street west from Church Street (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #12 Law School library (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #13 Elm Street east including Durfee Hall (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #14 East Rock (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #15 East Rock view toward West Rock (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #16 U.S. Postoffice - west sideof Church Street between Crown and Church Streets (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #17 Light House Point (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #18 The campus in snow (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #19 Abraham Pierson statue (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #20 Class of 1887on the senior fence (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - #21 View from East Rock toward the harbor and Mill River (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - #22 Northor United Church (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - #23 Center Church (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - #24 Chapel Street toward Durfee Hall (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - #25 Mount Carmel and the Sleeping Giant from East Rock (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - #26 The Divinity School (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - #27 Chapel Street west from College Street (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - #28 Trinity Church, State Capitol, Center Church (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - #29 City Hall and County Courthouse (then housed the Yale Law School), 1870-1880 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - #30 Class of 1872 in the old Chapel (from the pulpit toward the Green) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - #31"Old Guilford" (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - #32 Lafayette College - Eaton, PA (on the hill) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - #33 Durfee Hall (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - #34 Farnam Hall (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - #35 Viewof campus from Durfee Hall toward Chapel Street (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - #36 View from East Rock toward Fair Haven (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - #37old Library (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - #38 View of campus from Durfee Hall toward Chapel Street (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - #39 Dartmouth College (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - #40 Savin Rock - Sea View House (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - #41 Chapel Street Boathouse (west side) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - #42-43 Judges Cave (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - #44 Wintergreen Lake (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - #45 Wintergreen Falls (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - #46 Quinnipiac River (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - #47 Chaffy White's sail boats rented (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - #48-49 Savin Rock (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - #50-51 Savin Rock (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - #52 Center Church (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - #53 United Church (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - #54 Trinity Church (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - #55 Dartmouth College (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - #56 Football team on steps of the Art School (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - #57 Unidentified (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - #58 Boathouse on Lake Whitney (Day's Boathouse) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - #59-60 Missing
  - #61 Professor Norton's class in Chemical Engineering (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - #62 South on College Street from Elm Street (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - #63 Entrance to athletic field at Hamilton Park, Whalley Avenue (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - #64 West Rock (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - #65 City Hall and County Courthouse (Yale Law School) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - #66 Trinity Church (rear view) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - #67 Student room (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - #68 Student room [Class of 1878 or 1877s] (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - #69 Student room [Class of 1879] (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - #70 Student room (fraternity?) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - #71 Student room (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - #72 Student room of G.F. Bartlett, E.Y. Foote, A.D. Lewis, and I.K. Stetson, all 1879s. - Chi Phi Fraternity (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - #73 State Capitol, North Church (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - #74-75 Individual portraits (children) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - #76 Photograph of painting (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - #77-80 outdoor Scenes (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - #81 Chapel Street Boathouse (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - #82 Unidentified street corner (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - #83 Individual portrait (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - #84 outdoor scene (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - #85 Easton Chapel Street from South College (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - #86-87 Greenhouse (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - #88 Hillhouse Avenue toward the north (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - #89 Unidentified man (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - #90 Lake Whitney at Day's Boathouse (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - #91 Icehouses (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - #92-92 Dartmouth College (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - #94-95 Chi Phi Fraternity rooms? (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - #96 Chi Phi Fraternity room? (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - #97 Student room (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - # 98-99 Student rooms (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - #100-101 Student rooms (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - #102-103 Student rooms (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - #104-105 Student rooms - Durfee Hall (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - #106 Student room (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - #107 Student room of D. Thompson (Class of 1879), who shared it with H. Tufts (?) Sophomore year and N.A. Eddy, (Class of 1879) junior & senior years. (211 Durfee Hall) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - #108 Student room (Classof 1879) Chi Phi Fraternity (York Hall) (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - #109 Laboratory (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - #110-111 Student rooms (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - #112-113 Student rooms (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - #114-115 Student rooms (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - #116 Tug of war contest at Hamilton Park (Whalley Ave.) (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - #117old Brick Row and the Fence (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - #118 U.S. Post office - west side of Church Street between Crown and Center Streets (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - #119 View southeast from a Chapel Street building (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - #120 Light House Point (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - #121old Boathouse (Yale) (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - #122-122 Missing
  - #124 Student room (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - #125 Student room - Durfee Hall (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - #126-127 Student rooms - Durfee Hall (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - #128-129 Student rooms (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - #130-131 Student rooms (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - #132-133 Student rooms (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - #134 Durfee Hall (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - #135 South Sheffield Hall from the south sideof Grove Street looking northeast (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - #136 John Tuttle's store (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - #137 Wreath (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - #138 Unidentified house (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - #139 North end of College Street including South Sheffield Hall (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - #140 Eating Club - Elm Street (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - #141 North Sheffield Hall (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - #142 Unidentified building (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - #143 varsity crew in front of Durfee Hall, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - #144 Farnam Hall (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - #145 old Yale Fence - corner of College and Chapel Streets (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - #146 Entry group -old South (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - #147 Divinity School - northwest corner of Elm and College Streets (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - #148 Interior of church (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - #149 Varsity baseball team in front of Durfee Hall (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - #150 Interior of church (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - #150a old Fence in winter (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - #150b outdoor scene (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - #151 Unidentified building (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - #152 Class of 1870s members in front of North Sheffield Hall (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - #153 Student room (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - #154 Student room of Delta Psi man (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - #155 Theold Armory on Meadow Street (?) (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - #156 Athletic trophies (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - #157 View northeast from Insurance Buildings (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - #158 Law School - interior (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - #159 from East Rock toward New Haven Harbor (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - #160 South Sheffield Hall (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - #161 Dartmouth College (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - #162 Trinity Church (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - #163 old Brick Row and the Fence (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - #164 Whitney Avenue? (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - #165 East Rock (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - #166 West Rock and the section that was demolished for crushed stone (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - #167 Unidentified schooner (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - #168 Floral arrangement (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - #169 Bradley Point (near Savin Rock) (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - #170 Savin Rock (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - #171 View northeast from Insurance Building (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - #172 1842 Library (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - #173-174 Princeton University (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - #175 Harvard Dining Hall (Memorial Hall) (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - #176 Dartmouth College (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - #177 Entrance to Vassar College Grounds (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - #178 Princeton University (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - #179 House of the Skull and Bones Society (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - #180 Psi Upsilon Hall - west sideof High Street between Elm and Wall Streets (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - #181 The Athenaeum (The First Chapel) (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - #182 Class of 1874 on steps of State Capitol (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - #183 Fair Haven (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - #184 Yale Boathouse between the oldest and the Chapel Street Boathouse (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - #185 The telescope (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - #186 old Library - interior west toward entrance (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - #187 The old Chapel andold North (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - #188 The south pump - near the Lab (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - #189 Abraham Pierson statue (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - #190 Peabody Museum - southwest cornerof Elm and High Streets (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - #191 Buggy (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - #193 Chapel Street east from High Street (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - #192 The Freshman Row - Temple Street north of railroad bridge (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - #194 Chapel Street west from College Street including J.P. Beers' West End Drug Store (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - #195 View northwest from Insurance Building (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - #196 Indian Rock (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - #197 Durfee Hall (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - #198 Lafayette College, Easton, PA (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - #199 old South College (Union Hall) (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - #200 Connecticut Hall, Lyceum, North Middle College (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - #201 The First Gymnasium - corner of High and Library Streets (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - #202 Interior of Yale Gymnasium (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - #203-210 Missing
  - #211 Campus north from Chapel Street (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - #212 Interiorofold Chapel toward pulpit (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - #213 The Art School (now Street Hall) (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - #214 East and West Divinity (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - #215 View toward Fair Haven from East Rock (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - #216 View toward the harbor from East Rock (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - #217 The Sleeping Giant (Mt. Carmel) from East Rock (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - #218 View west from East Rock including St. Francis' orphan Asylum (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - #219 Corner of Chapel and Church Streets including Franklin Elm (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - #220 Temple Street north from Chapel Street (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - #221 Lake Whitney from East Rock (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - #222 Viewof New Haven from East Rock (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - #223 Fence and campus north from Chapel Street (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - #224 College Street south from Elm Street (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - #225 Chapel Street east from High Street (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - #226 Chapel Street west from College Street (Gulliver's Store is second on left) (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - #227 Hillhouse Avenue from Grove Street (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - #228 Hillhouse Avenue north from the railroad bridge (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - #229 High Street south from Elm Street (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - #230 Church Street north from Crown Street (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - #231 Lake Saltonstall showing the rowing course (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - #232 Lake Saltonstall looking south (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - #233 East Rock and Indian (?) Rock (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - #234 East Rock from Orange Street (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - #235 York Street north from Crown Street (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - #236 Unidentified street (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - #237 Elm Street east from Durfee Hall (after Battell Chapel was built) (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - #238 Weston Elm Street from opposite Hendrie Hall (before West Divinity and Battell Chapel) (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - #239 Old Torrent (fire engine) (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - #240 Horse (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - #241 Group of soldiers standing near monument (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - #242 Unidentified street (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - #243old South College and students on the Senior Fence (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - #244 Soldiers marching on street (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - #245 [Interior of German Baptist Church] - corner of Broad and George Streets (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - #246 German Baptist Church (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - #247 Group in front of Hopkins Grammar School (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - #238 Unidentified building (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - #249-251 Missing
  - #252 Sigma Delta Chi Fraternity - 36 Elm Street (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - #253 North end of College Street including South Sheffield Hall (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - #254 Temple Street houses between Chapel & Wall Streets (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - #255-256 Nature scenes (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - #257 Unidentified machine (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - #258 Hillhouse High School - cornerof Orange and Grove Streets (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - #259 South Sheffield Hall from south side of Grove Street (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - #260 Mory's - southeast corner of Temple and Center Streets (The Temple Bars) (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - #261a Individual portrait (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - #261 Abraham Pierson statue on original site facing Chapel Street (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - #262-263 Missing
  - #262a Unidentified machine (Box 3, Folder 99)